Guide to the Paul Moody Atkins Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PROFESSIONAL FILES, 1919-1936; Series I
  - Rutgers University
    - General
      - Manuals: students, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 235)
      - Teaching materials
        - Finance, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 236)
        - "Industrial Managerial Problems", 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 237)
        - Lectures and notes, 1966-1976 (Box 25, Folder 238)
        - Supplemental readings, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 239)
    - "Rutgers Report on World Affairs"
      - Text of reports, 1963-1972 (Box 25, Folder 240-241)
      - Drafts of reports, 1963-1973 (Box 25, Folder 242-243)
    - Speaking engagements, 1964-1974 (Box 25, Folder 244-245)
  - Writings
    - Articles: published, 1919-1923 (Box 26, Folder 246-247)
    - Articles: published (two volumes), 1919-1927 (Box 27, Folder 248)
    - Articles: published (two volumes), 1928-1940; 1942 (Box 28, Folder 249)
    - Articles: published
      - "Dakar and the Strategy of West French Africa", 1942 (Box 28, Folder 250)
      - "French West Africa in Wartime", 1942 (Box 28, Folder 251)
    - Articles: published - miscellaneous, 1920-1968 (Box 29, Folder 252)
    - Books: published— Textbook of Industrial Cost Accounting, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 253)
    - Writings: unpublished
      - "Higher Technological and Commercial Education in France and the U. S.", 1925 (Box 30, Folder 254-255)
      - "The Administrative Control of Stores Material", 1926 (Box 30, Folder 256-257)
      - "Practical Factory Cost Accounting for the Small Scale Enterprise", 1926 (Box 30, Folder 258)
      - "University Training for Industry and Commerce in France and the United States"
        - Draft, 1926, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 259-266)
      - "The Causes and Prospects of the Present European Conflict", 1939 (Box 31, Folder 267-268)
      - "Mainsprings of the War", 1940 (Box 31, Folder 269)
      - "The Story Behind the War News", [ca 1940] (Box 31, Folder 270-271)
      - "The West African Menace", 1941 (Box 31, Folder 272-274)
      - Dakar—Key to the Atlantic, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 275-277)
      - "What Iran Means to Americans", 1946 (Box 31, Folder 278)
      - "The Possibilities of Technical Assistance in World Economic Reconstruction", 1949 (Box 31, Folder 279)
      - "Technical Assistance to Underdeveloped Countries", 1949 (Box 31, Folder 280)
      - "An Analysis of the International Chamber of Commerce", 1952 (Box 31, Folder 281-282)
      - "The Meaning of Automation to Business and Employment", 1955 (Box 32, Folder 283)
      - "Life Insurance: An Aid to the Solution of Business Problems", 1956-1958 (Box 32, Folder 284-288)
      - "Investment Portfolio Management", 1958 (Box 32, Folder 289-291)
      - "And Bombs Bursting in Air", undated (Box 32, Folder 292)
      - "Dakar-Key to the Atlantic", undated (Box 32, Folder 293)
      - "The Future Trend of Interest Rates", undated (Box 32, Folder 294)
      - "Minorities and the Peace of Europe", undated (Box 32, Folder 295)
      - "The Present War-How Did It Start and Where Is It Going?", undated (Box 32, Folder 296)
      - "The Relationship of Cost to Prices", undated (Box 32, Folder 297)
      - "Russia and the Present War (fragment)", undated (Box 32, Folder 298)
      - "A History of the United States for People of Other Countries"
        - English text, undated (Box 33, Folder 299-300)
        - French text, undated (Box 33, Folder 301-302)
        - Spanish text, undated (Box 33, Folder 303-304)
  - Oversized financial charts, Circa 1920-1940 (Box 48)
    Bond rates, government debt, interest rates, export/import rates and other financial data are recorded monthly.
- FAMILY AND PERSONAL PAPERS, 1749-1976; Series II; 14 boxes (5.5') 2 folios
  This series contains correspondence, diaries, photos, printed material, memorabilia, and miscellanea.
  The series is arranged in two sections: Family papers and Personal papers. Each section is arranged alphabetically by the type of material.
  Boxes 34 and 35 are available on microfilm (HM 168).
  - Family Papers
    - Bergier, Henri
      - Diary: World War I
        Conditions Governing Access
        These records have been microfilmed and are available on HM 168; originals are restricted.
        - Copy: typescript, 1914-1918 (Box 34, Folder 305-314)
        - Correspondence, 1918-1926 (Box 35, Folder 315)
        - Photographs and miscellanea, [ca 1890-1926] (Box 35, Folder 316)
        - Text: original, 1914-1918 (Box 35, Folder 317-321)
    - Genealogy
      - Charts, undated (Box 36, Folder 322)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1930; 1937; 1940 (Box 36, Folder 323)
        - Yale University Library, 1944-1957 (Box 36, Folder 324)
      - Lists, undated (Box 36, Folder 325)
      - Printed material
        - General, 1912; 1931; 1944 (Box 36, Folder 326)
        - Moody Family, 1847 (Box 36, Folder 327)
        - Williams, Abraham, 1749 (Box 36, Folder 328)
    - Memorabilia and miscellanea
      - Atkins, David P.: miscellanea, Circa 1932-1940 (Box 37, Folder 329)
      - Atkins, Edward: birth and marriage certificates, 1880; 1924 (Box 37, Folder 330)
      - Atkins, Edward Moody: miscellanea, 1933-1943 (Box 37, Folder 331)
      - Atkins, Genevieve B.
        - Bookplates and postcards, undated (Box 37, Folder 332)
        - Memorabilia
          - France, 1894-1920 (Box 37, Folder 333)
            - Oversized certificates and diplomas, 1909-1917 (Box 49)
          - Syracuse University, 1919-1920 (Box 37, Folder 334)
            - Oversized diploma, 1920 (Box 49)
      - Atkins, Henri B.: miscellanea, 1937-1950 (Box 37, Folder 335)
      - Atkins, Paul Moody
        - Letters of recommendation, 1911-1949 (Box 37, Folder 336)
        - Military appointments and miscellaneous, 1918-1955 (Box 37, Folder 337)
        - Military yearbook, 1918 (Box 37, Folder 338)
        - Miscellanea, Circa 1911-1942 (Box 37, Folder 339)
      - Photographs
        - Atkins, David P., 1922; 1936; 1944 (Box 38, Folder 340)
        - Atkins, Edward, 1910-1943; undated (Box 38, Folder 341)
        - Atkins, Edward M., 1936; 1942; 1944 (Box 38, Folder 342)
        - Atkins, Genevieve B., 1912-1957; undated (Box 38, Folder 343)
        - Atkins, Henri B., 1936; 1942; 1944 (Box 38, Folder 344)
        - Atkins, Marjorie, 1895-1906 (Box 38, Folder 345)
        - Atkins, Martha, 1878; 1882; undated (Box 38, Folder 346)
        - Atkins, Paul M., 1914-1957; undated (Box 38, Folder 347)
        - Brichett(?), John and Moody, Mary C., undated (Box 38, Folder 348)
        - Moody, Martha B., undated (Box 38, Folder 349)
        - Groups, 1928-1958 (Box 38, Folder 350)
        - Miscellaneous relatives, undated (Box 38, Folder 351)
  - Personal Papers
    - Correspondence
      - C. I. A., 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 352)
      - China-visa, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 353)
      - F. B. I., 1976 (Box 39, Folder 354)
      - Internal Revenue Service, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 355)
      - Russell, Malcolm, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 356)
      - U. S. Congress
        - General, 1968-1975 (Box 39, Folder 357-358)
        - Angola, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 359)
        - Energy, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 360)
        - Oil companies, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 361)
        - Supreme Court, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 362)
        - Vietnam, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 363)
        - Watergate, 1973-1974 (Box 39, Folder 364)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Family, 1972-1973 (Box 40, Folder 365-367)
      - Letters to the editor, 1968; 1971 (Box 40, Folder 368)
    - Student papers
      - Miss Seeger's School, 1902; undated (Box 41, Folder 369)
        - Oversized diploma, 1902 June 12 (Box 49)
      - Roxbury Latin School
        - Student materials, 1907-1911 (Box 41, Folder 370)
        - Notebooks, 1910 (Box 41, Folder 371)
        - Oversized diploma, 1910 June 16 (Box 49)
        - Alumni material, 1946; 1970 (Box 41, Folder 372)
      - Yale University
        - Alumni material, 1963-1975 (Box 42, Folder 373)
        - Correspondence, 1914; 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 374)
        - Oversized diplomas, 1914-1915 (Box 49)
        - Scrapbook documenting life at Yale, 1910-1914 (Box 48)
        - Student grades, 1911-1914 (Box 42, Folder 375)
        - Student papers, 1911-1914 (Box 42, Folder 376)
        - Student publications and miscellaneous, 1913-1914; undated (Box 42, Folder 377)
      - Université de Paris
        - Oversized diploma, 1925 June 12 (Box 49)
        - Ph. D. dissertation, 1925 (Box 42, Folder 378)
        - Student forms, 1924-1925 (Box 42, Folder 379)
      - Armour Institute of Technology, Circa 1920-1926, 1975
        - Engineering drawings, Circa 1920-1926 (Box 49)
        - Resolution to perpetuate name after merger with Illinois Institute of Technology, 1975 (Box 49)
    - Miscellanea, 1920-1928; undated (Box 42, Folder 380)
    - Travel logs
      - 1923 April - August (Box 43, Folder 381)
      - 1923 August - November (Box 44, Folder 382)
      - 1923 November - 1924 January (Box 45, Folder 383)
      - 1924 January - March (Box 46, Folder 384)
      - 1924 March - May (Box 47, Folder 385)